So, let's go into the Route 53 console.
And to get started with Amazon Route 53,
you need to register a domain.
So on the left-hand side, click on Registered domains,
but this will cost you money.
So if you don't wanna do it, then just watch me do.
I'm going to register a domain.
And I have to choose a domain name so, stephane-ccp.com.
Let's see if someone took it.
And no one took it, it's available for me,
so I'm going to buy it for 12 dollars a year.
I'll add it to my cart and then I will click on continue.
Then, I have to register my information,
so I'll just do that offline.
And then, my order is completed
and it will take a bit of time to get processed.
So for this, I can go to my domains
and I can see the domain registration is in progress.
So after a while, maybe ten, fifteen minutes,
you will see your domain, stephane-ccp.com
and you will see its expiration date and so on.
So once you have done this,
you go into the left-hand side into Hosted zones.
And the hosted zones, you will have one created,
which is stephane-ccp.com.
And, this is where we're going to place our DNS records.
And currently we should only have two DNS records,
but we're going to create EC2 instances
and then, DNS records to point to them.
So, let's go ahead and create EC2 instances.
So, I'm gonna go into the EC2 console
in the region I'm in right now,
which is going to be the Ireland region, right here.
And I'm going to create our first EC2 instance
that's going to say, hello from whatever the region.
So I will launch the instance
and then, I will just scroll down
where I'm going to be a little bit quicker on this
because we've done this before.
So, I will proceed without a key pair.
I will select create a new security group
that allows HTTP traffic.
No need for SSH, so HTTP is enough.
And then, we're going to scroll down.
And under advanced details,
we're going to add some user data.
And, I will just post this.
And instead of hello world from host name,
we're gonna say, "Hello world from Ireland". Okay.
Next, I'm going to launch this instance.
And, we have one instance launching right now
in this region.
So, I'm going to click on it
and I'm going to get the public IP from this instance.
So, here it is.
And, I'm going to just save this
in, in a new file in here, just to have a reference to it.
So, Ireland is this IP.
And then what I'm going to do is,
I'm going to switch regions.
So maybe, I'll go to US West two, so Oregon.
And, I'm going to do the exact same thing.
So, I will launch instances and I will scroll down.
Instance type, I will choose a T2 Micro.
So as you can see, it's a bit slower.
So, this is because we're in a region
that's further away from me.
So, it's a good example of a latency.
I will create a security group again
and it will just allow HTTP traffic from anywhere.
And for advance details, again,
I'm going to copy the user data from before.
And this one is going to be "Hello world from the US". Okay.
Next, I'm going to launch my instance
and go in the console to find it.
So now, we have two instances being launched.
So, we have one in the Ireland region
and one in the US West two region.
So, they're further, far away from each other.
And, if I go to this first IPV four address and go for it,
I get the "Hello world from Ireland".
So, this is working just fine.
And, I'm going to pause for this instance
to start running and get back to you.
Now, if I go to this instance
and look at the public IPV four address and paste it,
I get a "Hello world from the US".
So, this is awesome.
We have an instance in Ireland and an instance in the US.
So now, let's go into Route 53.
So, here I am.
And, I'm going to actually create records.
So, we're going to create our first record
and the sub-domain is going to be www.stephane-ccp.com.
It's a type of record which is the A type of record.
And the value is going to be,
the value of my instance in Ireland.
So I copy this and paste it, and you need to remove the htp
if it does, if it does get copied.
And, the routing policy
is going to be a Latency based policy
because I wanna be routed to the instance
that is the closest to me in terms of Latency.
So this instance right here, is in the EU-West one region.
So I will just type it, EU-West one and I have it.
And then, the record ID will say my,
my instance from Ireland.
And, we can add another record underneath.
So again, for www.stephane-ccp.com,
same thing as in A record.
This time the value is going to be this IP right here.
So, I copy it and paste it.
And then, the routing policy is again a Latency
but this time, the region that this is in
is the US-West two,
which is Oregon.
And, the record is, "My US Instance".
Okay. So here, that means
that for the www, we have two records.
One associated with the US-West region and one
with the EU regions.
So, let's create these records.
And as you can see in here, you can look at the Latency
for two of these instances.
So now, we should go ahead and test this.
So, if I open a new tab and go to www.stephane-ccp.com
and press enter.
As you can see, I get a "Hello World from Ireland".
So, this is the instance
that is the closest to me, of course.
And if I refresh this page, of course,
I'm going to remain on the hello world from Ireland.
But if I use a VPN, and this is Nord VPN that I'm using
and connect to another country.
So for example, the United States.
Now, it will look like my connection
is coming from the United States, Okay.
So, I open a new private window and go to stephane-ccp.com.
And as you can see, I get a hello world back from the US
because my connection is closest to my US based instance.
So, that's it for this lecture.
So, we've demonstrated how Route 53 was allowing us
to create a record that would basically guide us
to the instance that has the least latency versus us, okay,
compared to us.
So, this is all you need to know for the scope of Route 53
at the exam, but of course,
if you're going to an associate level exam
then you need to learn more about
how to use different types of records,
what they mean, and so on.
So to clean up, just make sure to terminate your instances
in the various regions so that you don't have any cost.
So, you can terminate this one
and you can terminate that one as well.
And then also lastly, you can choose if you wanted to
to delete the hosted zones, stephane-ccp.com
or whatever you have chosen for your domain name.
This will cost you 50 cents per month, but no matter what,
the domain that you have purchased
before will cost you around 12 dollars per year.
So if you don't want to pay again 12 dollars next year,
please make sure to disable the auto renewal.
Okay. So, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.